프리티 리틀 라이어스 지난 이야기
Previously on Pretty Little Liars...
에즈라 선생님을
어디로 옮기는지 알아내서
We'll find out where they're taking him
거기에 데려다 줄게
and we'll get you there.
계획은 오늘밤에
알리를 탈출시키는 거였지만
The plan was to get Ali out of town tonight
이제는 A가
에즈라를 쫓는다는걸 알잖아
but now that we know
that "A's" after Ezra...
I get that "A" wants to shut Ezra up,
A가 에즈라 선생님의
입을 막길 원하다는 건 알지만
but Ali's still a target.
알리는 여전히 타겟이야
Exactly what is it you want us to do?
정확히 우리가
뭘 하길 원하는 건데?
I want us to stick together.
우리가 단결하길 원해
The bigger we are, the harder she falls.
우리가 거대해 질 수록
앨리슨 더 심하게 망가질테니까
- Oh, my God.
- Look at her!
- 세상에
- 쟤 좀 봐!
- Are you okay?
- What happened?
- 너 괜찮니?
- 무슨 일이야?
I saw Mrs. DiLaurentis in the woods,
숲에서 딜로렌티스 부인을 봤고
부인을 미행하려고 했어
and I tried to follow her.
She was giving a suitcase to somebody,
부인은 누군가에게
가방을 건네고 있었는데
난 그게 알리일 거라 생각했어
and I thought maybe it was Ali.
Jason, what's going on?
제이슨 오빠, 웬일이예요?
I kind of need to keep a little space
나와 스펜서 사이에
- between me and Spencer.
- Why?
- 다소 거리를 둘 필요가 있어
- 왜요?
My mom needs me right now,
and I'm here to help her.
우리엄마에겐 지금 내가 필요하고
엄마를 돕기 위해 여기 있는 거야
- This isn't a game.
- So what is it?
- 이건 게임이 아냐
- 그럼 왜 그러는데?
- Justice.
- SPENCER: For who?
- 정의를 위해
- 누굴 위한 정의?
Jenna.
제나를 위해서구나
- (door opens)
- Spencer!
스펜서!
- Surprise!
- Hey, Shana!
- 놀라운데요!
- 야, 샤나!
- (gunshot)
- (screaming)
- You did what you had to do.
- Let's go home.
- 넌 해야할 일을 한 거야
- 집에 가자
(brakes squeak)
감사합니다
Thanks.
Ali, are you okay?
알리, 괜찮은 거니?
Stop.
그만
You don't need to run anymore.
넌 더이상 도망칠 필요가 없어
"A" is gone. Come on.
A는 죽었어. 가자
Ali, look... we talked about this.
알리, 봐봐...우린 얘기했잖아
You know it's the right decision.
그게 옳은 결정이라는 걸
넌 알아
Maybe I should go home
first... speak to my mom.
집에 먼저 가 봐야 할지도...
엄마와 얘길해 봐야지
Ali, your mother buried you.
알리, 너희 엄마가 널 묻었었어
Look, I think it's more important that
너희 엄마가 널 매장할 때
the police know you're
alive before your mom does.
넌 살아 있었다는 걸
경찰이 아는 게 중요하다고 생각해
Hey, yeah. You need to walk in there
그래. 넌 저기로 가서
and tell them everything.
경찰에게 모든 걸 말해야 해
I mean, about Mona being "A,"
모나가 A였다는 것과
Shana taking over where
Mona left off... all of it.
모나가 멈춘 후엔
샤나가 넘겨받았다는...그 모든 것들을
Start with the night that you ran away.
니가 도망치던
그 밤부터 시작해야지
No. Before that you have to
start with the Jenna thing.
아니. 그 전에
제나의 사건부터 시작해야지
- Wait, what? Why?
- She has to.
- 잠깐, 뭐라구? 뭐하러?
- 그렇게 해야 돼
Shana was after us for payback
for what happened to Jenna.
제나에게 있었던 일에 대한 복수를 위해
샤나는 우리를 쫓아온 거니까
- I can't do this.
- I can't.
나 이거 못 하겠다
난 못 한다구
You can. Okay, you're not in this alone.
넌 할 수 있어
넌 이번엔 혼자가 아니야
"A" tortured all of us,
and what happened to Shana...
A는 우리 모두를 괴롭혔고
샤나에게 일어난 일은...
Happened because of me.
내가 저지른 일이야
And I can handle that part. I think.
그 부분은 내가 할 수 있어
그렇게 생각해
But, Ali, look, you're
gonna have to cover the rest.
하지만, 알리, 봐봐
나머지 부분들은 네가 처리해야 돼
로즈우드 경찰서
Ali.
알리
Are we in agreement?
우리 합의한 거지?
- (indistinct conversations)
- (phone beeping)
- 홀브룩 형사님이세요?
- 그래
I think you've been looking for me.
형사님이 저를
찾고 있었다고 생각해요
- I'm...
- I know who you are.
- 저는...
- 네가 누군지 안다
I'm glad you're with your
friends. Welcome home.
친구들과 함께라 기쁘구나
돌아온 걸 환영한다
I'm guessing you have a lot to tell me.
내게 이야기 해 줄 것이
많을 것 같구나
Maybe we can begin with the
night that you disappeared.
네가 사라져버린 그 밤부터
시작해야 되겠지
(zipper closes)
I didn't disappear.
저는 사라진 게 아니였어요
I was kidnapped.
납치당한 거였어요
I was kidnapped and held
hostage for two years,
납치당해서 2년 동안 인질로 있었고
and if it weren't for my friends,
친구들이 없었다면
여기 서있을 수 없었을 거예요
친구들이 내 목숨을 구했어요
I wouldn't be standing
here. They saved my life.
♪ Got a secret ♪
Pretty Little Liars
S05 x E02 Whirly Girl (속물근성의 소녀)
♪ Can you keep it? ♪
♪ Swear this one you'll save ♪
♪ Better lock it, in your pocket ♪
영문자막 chamallow
♪ Taking this one to the grave ♪
♪ If I show you, then I know you ♪
한글자막 적과의 동침
♪ Won't tell what I said ♪
♪ 'Cause two can keep a secret ♪
출처 미드나잇 / DC 인사이드 기미갤
♪ If one of them is dead ♪
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
누가 이 사진을 찍었는진 모르지만
날짜가 찍혀있기에
We don't know who took
this photo, but it is dated,
so I'm assuming this wasn't
your first visit home.
이번이 네가 처음으로
집을 방문한 것이 아니라고 추측하고 있다
You have any memory of this night?
이날 밤에 대한 기억이 있니?
It was the night that I got away from him.
제가 그 사람으로부터
도망친 밤이었어요
From your captor?
납치한 사람으로부터?
How?
어떻게?
- I jumped out of the car.
- While you were blindfolded?
- 차에서 뛰어 내렸죠
- 눈가리개를 하고 있었는데도?
Yeah, I tore it off, and I
ran straight into the woods
네, 눈가리개를 벗고
바로 숲을 향해 달렸고
so that he couldn't catch me.
그는 저를 잡지 못 했어요
But on the night of this photo,
사진이 찍힌 그 밤에
you managed to make it
back to Rosewood and...
넌 로즈우드로 돌아오려고 했었고...
you found your friends.
넌 네 친구들을 발견한 거야
I asked them to hide me.
애들에게 저를 숨겨달라고 했죠
You thought that they would be
more helpful than the police?
쟤들이 경찰보다
더 도움이 될 거라 생각했던 거니?
Your parents?
네 부모님 보다도?
I was scared.
무서웠어요
Okay, I was scared that if I came back home
그래요, 제가 집에
돌아온 것이 밝혀지면
그가 나를
다시 찾아낼 게 무서웠어요
and I was out in the open
that he'd find me again.
So how did you protect her?
그럼 너희들은
어떻게 앨리슨을 보호했니?
They hid me in the woods.
애들이 숲에 저를 숨겨줬어요
In a shed that we all used to hang out in.
숲에 숨어 있다가
우리들은 시간을 보냈죠
After school, the weekends.
방과 후랑 주말에요
But you just said that they came
to your rescue in Philadelphia.
하지만 너를 구하기 위해서
쟤들이 필라델피아로 왔다고 방금 말했잖아
(door opens)
(sighs) Dad!
아빠!
- Oh, my God!
- Dad.
- 이럴 수가!
- 아빠!
Was I sleeping on that bus?
버스에서 내가 잔 거야?
When did we discuss kidnapping?
납치됐던 걸로 하자고
언제 우리가 쇼부 본 거야?
- We didn't.
- Why is it just her dad?
- 그런 적 없지
- 알리의 아빠는 웬일이지?
- Where is her mother?
- I don't know.
- 알리의 엄마는 어디 계시지?
- 모르지
Emily, call your mother.
에밀리, 어머니께 전화드려라
Her flight from Dallas was
canceled because of the storms.
달라스에서 오는 비행기편이
태풍 때문에 취소됐다는 구나
You're welcome to stay here
as long as you need to.
네가 필요한 만큼
여기서 지내도 좋아
Thank you.
감사합니다
I'll, uh, I'll call her from outside.
저는, 음, 나가서 전화드릴게요
Hold it.
기다려
Where are you going?
어딜 가는 게냐?
I am so tired.
피곤해서요
위 층에 가서 샤워나 하려고...
I just wanted to go
upstairs and take a shower...
그리고는 주무시겠다? 진심이니?
And go to bed? Really?
Without telling me where you've
been for the past few days?
지난 며칠간 어디에 있었는지
엄마에게 말도 없이?
You might have a hard time
falling asleep if I'm poking you
내가 5초마다
새로운 질문들을 던져대면
every five seconds with a new question.
넌 잠들기 어려울 것 같은데
You knew Alison was alive for over a month
한 달여 전 부터
앨리슨이 살아있다는 걸 알고 있었는데
- and you never said a word?
- I didn't mean to...
- 넌 한마디도 안한 거니?
- 저는 그럴 수가...
Why would you keep this kind of secret?
왜 이걸 비밀로 한 거냐?
Because we made a promise.
우린 약속했으니까요
Well, you obviously
didn't think it through.
그렇다면, 넌 분명
어찌 될지 생각하지 않은 거구나
Did you?
그런 거니?
Because there's still a dead girl
앨리슨의 무덤에
in Alison's grave that the police...
아직 죽은 소녀가 있기 때문에 경찰은...
I don't know who that is.
And I had nothing to do with it,
그 소녀가 누군지 모르고
저와는 상관 없는 일이구요
and whether you believe me
or not, Mom, that is the truth.
저를 믿던 못 믿던
엄마, 그건 사실이예요
(sobbing)
Wait.
기다려라
I'm not accusing you of anything
right now but poor judgment.
지금 너를 비난 하는 것이 아니라
판단이 서지 않아서야
While you were gone,
네가 없는 동안
네 아빠와 나는
경찰서에 끌려 갔었다
your father and I were
dragged down to that precinct.
What? Where's Dad?
뭐라구요?
아빠 어딨어요?
In Philly.
필라델피아에
They found your car and impounded it.
거기서 네 차가 발견됐고 압류됐어
He went down there with
Melissa to get it out.
그걸 해결하기 위해
멜리사와 함께 가셨다
Wait! Melissa's here?
잠깐요! 언니 여깄어요?
Is she back from London?
런던에서 돌아온 거예요?
Oh, yes! And don't expect any souvenirs,
오, 그래! 어떤 기념품도
기대하지 마렴
그녀가 가지고 돌아온 건
완고한 태도니까
because all she brought back was attitude.
And secrets.
비밀들도 갖고 왔지
Go on get ready for bed.
가서 잘 준비 하거라
ASHLEY: Did you ever plan
on telling me the truth?
내게 사실을 말할 생각은 있었니?
Of course I did.
물론 있었죠
But we had to wait until it felt safe.
하지만 우린 안전하다고 느낄 때까진
기다려야 했어요
You feel that way now?
이젠 안전하다고 느끼니?
- Yeah. Kind of.
- How?
- 네. 어느 정도는요
- 어떻게?
The person who did this to
Alison is still out there.
앨리슨에게 그 짓을 한 자가
아직 어딘가에 있잖아
Is this cheese old?
이 치즈 오래된 거예요?
It's Havarti.
그거 하바티야
- Does it melt?
- All cheese melts, Hanna.
- 그거 녹아요?
- 모든 치즈는 녹아, 한나
Hey! Look at me.
야! 나 좀 봐
How did you feel when you found
out Alison was still alive?
앨리슨이 살아있다는 걸 알았을 때
어떤 기분이었니?
What do you mean?
그게 무슨 말이예요?
Sweetie.
얘야
You have kept a lot of secrets from me,
넌 내게 많은 걸
비밀로 하지만
but this one is right up there
with The Manhattan Project.
이건 *맨하탄 프로젝트와 맞먹는 일이라구
세계 2차 대전 당시 미국의 원자폭탄 계획
The what?
그게 뭐죠?
I don't understand how
you got up in the morning,
앨리슨이 여전히
위험하다는 걸 알면서도
went to school, knowing that
Alison was still in danger.
넌 어떻게 아침에 일어나고
학교에 갔었는지 이해할 수가 없구나
That poor girl must just be...
그 불쌍한 아이는 분명...
엄마, 앨리슨은 그만하길 원해요, 아시겠죠?
Mom, she wants to move on. Okay?
And the more people talk about
it and ask a billion questions,
사람들이 그 얘기를 하고
수백만가지 질문을 해댈 수록
the harder it's gonna be for her!
앨리슨은 더 힘들어질 거라구요!
Yes, it was a nightmare,
네, 그건 악몽이었지만
but it's over and she needs it to end.
다 끝났구요
앨리슨은 그만 하길 원한다구요
Hey.
얘야
Just sit down, okay? I'll make this for you.
앉아보겠니?
널 위해 그러는 거야
네. 핏츠요. F-I-T-Z
토요일날 입원해서
Yes. It's Fitz. F-I-T-Z.
He got admitted on Saturday
- and he had surgery.
- (door knocks)
수술을 받았어요
Yeah, come in.
네, 들어오세요
Oh! I thought you were Dad.
오! 아빠인 줄 알았어
No. He's downstairs. Hey...
아니. 아빠는 아래층에 계셔. 누나...
Is it true?
그게 사실이야?
앨리슨 누나가 살아서
집으로 돌아왔다구?
Is Alison alive and back in her house?
와우. 미쳤구나
Wow. That's insane.
아빠가 엄마에게 말하는 걸 들었는데
어떤 똘아이가 그 누나 눈을 가리고...
I heard Dad telling Mom that some
freak had her blind-folded, and...
It's not a video game, Mike.
이건 비디오 게임이 아니야, 마이크
I'm not making a joke.
농담하고 있는 거 아니야
She's tough. I'm kind of surprised
그 누나 터프하잖아
그녀가 맨손으로
그 똘아이를 죽이지 않은 것에
조금 놀랐다구
she didn't kill the
creep with her bare hands.
Just stop.
그만 좀 해
제발! 그만
Please! Stop.
Why is Mr. Fitz in the hospital?
핏츠 선생님은 왜 병원에 있어?
What?
뭐?
The door is made of wood, not plutonium.
문은 나무로 되어 있어
플루토늄이 아니라구
주말에 뉴욕에 있다가 다쳤어
He's in New York for the
weekend, and he got hurt.
What happened? Is he gonna be okay?
무슨 일이었는데?
선생님은 괜찮은 거야?
Yeah. He's gonna be fine.
그래. 좋아질 거야
어제 그를 봤어
곧 괜찮아질 거야
I saw him yesterday. He
is gonna be just fine.
잠깐. 선생님은 뉴욕에 있다고 했잖아
Wait. You said he was in New York.
누나들 필라델피아에 있었다면
어떻게 선생님을 본 거야?
How did you see him if
you guys were in Philly?
그를 본 건 아니야
이야기만 했어
I didn't see him. I spoke to him.
마이크, 나 기진맥진이야
자러 가야겠어
Look, Mike, I'm exhausted,
so I'm gonna go to sleep.
(sighs)
She never saw this person,
Mom. She only heard his voice.
앨리슨은 그 사람을 보지 못 했어요, 엄마
단지 목소리만 들었어요
그가 앨리슨을 방이나
그런 곳에 가뒀었던 것 같아요
I... I guess he had her
locked in a room or...
I don't know.
모르겠어요
저기요, 나중에 얘기할 수 있죠?
부탁이예요
Look, can we talk about this later? Please.
알겠어요
Okay.
Yeah. I love you, too.
네. 저도 사랑해요
끊어요
Bye.
(phone beeps)
무슨 일이야?
What's wrong?
What's not?
이유가 뭐냐구?
우린 합의했었잖아, 에밀리
We made a pact, Emily.
A는 결국 죽었고
우리의 생활로 돌아올 모든 준비가 됐었는데
"A" is finally dead, and we were
all ready to get back to our lives,
이제 갑자기 우린
앨리슨의 혹성으로 돌아와 버렸어
and now all of a sudden
we're back on Planet Alison.
Okay, Spencer...
그래, 스펜서...
처음부터 다시
9학년이 된 것 같다구
It's like it's 9th grade all over again,
그리고 우린 여기서
*Whirly Girl (속물근성의 소녀)에 올라타는 거지
and we are here on "The
Whirly Girlie Ride."
알리는 악당이 되고
우린 그저 걔의 이야기의 배경이 되길 바라는 거지
And Ali goes rogue, and we're
just expected to backup her story.
넌 심지어 거짓말이나 덧붙이고 있어
You're even adding to the lie.
왜 아직도 알리가
우릴 통제하는 거지?
Why is she still controlling us?
Maybe she flipped last minute
지난 번에 알리가 입장을 바꾼건
자신의 엄마를
보호하고 싶었기 때문일 거야
because she wanted to protect her mom.
경찰에 털어놓기 전에
Maybe she wanted to hear why her mom
자신의 엄마가 왜 그랬었는지
did what she did before it gets
듣고 싶었던 걸거야
forced out of her by the police.
지금 알리를 변호하면서
정말 여기서 지내고 싶은 거야?
Are you really gonna stay
here and defend Ali right now?
그게 아니라...
- I am not...
- (door opens)
(leaves rustling)
자동차 청소하기에
Okay. Is it just me or
정말 이상한 시간이라는 걸
나만 느끼는 건 아닐거야
it's really a weird
time to detail your car.
제이슨 오빠는
앨리슨이 집에 온 걸 모르나?
Does Jason not know that she is home?
Of course he knows.
당연히 알죠
(car door slams)
정말 묻고 싶은건
The only question is why would you be
죽었던 여동생이
살아 돌아 온다면
squee-gee-ing your backseat if your sister
자동차 뒤 좌석을
청소하냐는 거지
just got back from the dead?
(crickets chirping)
(window creaking)
- 그게 뭐야?
- 앨리슨의 전화기야?
- What is that?
- Her phone?
뉴욕에서 있었던 사실이
널 묻어버릴 거다
_
이거 누가 보낸 거야?
Who sent you this?
MR. DiLAURENTIS: Hey, you there...
거기 있었구나...
네가 오늘밤에 아래층에서
자기를 원할거라고 생각하고 있었다
I was thinking maybe you
wanna sleep downstairs tonight,
you won't have to be in here by yourself.
너 혼자 여기 있어서는 안됐는데
괜찮아요, 아빠
It's okay, Dad.
오랫동안 이 순간을 꿈꿔왔는 걸요
I've been dreaming about
this moment for a long time...
내 침대에서 잠자는 걸요
sleeping in my own bed.
이해한다...난 그저...
I understand... I just...
널 다시 내 시야 밖에 두는 건
생각할 수 없어서
I don't think I can ever let
you out of my sight again.
Have you heard from mom?
엄마는 어딨는지 들으셨어요?
아, 네 오빠와 난
네 엄마와 연락하려 해왔다
Ah, your brother and I had
been trying to reach her,
걱정하지 않는다고는
말할 순 없구나
I can't say I'm not worried, because I am.
엄마는 잘 계실 거예요
I'm sure she's fine.
앨리슨
Alison,
아마도 너무 많은 걸
바란다는 건 알지만
I know this is maybe asking for too much,
하지만...음...
네가 안전하다고 느꼈으면 해
but... um... I want you to feel safe.
길가 가장자리에
장벽을 세워달라고
I've asked the police to put up a barrier
경찰에 요청했단다
at the end of the street.
많은 사람들이
네 이야기를 듣고 싶어하겠지만
Lot of people are gonna
wanna hear your story,
넌 집을 나선다거나
누구와 이야기를 해선 안 된다
but you don't have to leave
this house or talk to anybody
네가 준비가 될 때까진 말이다
until you're ready.
내가...
I...
네게 지난 몇 년을 되돌려줄 순 없다
I can't give you those years back.
앨리슨, 내가 할 순 없어, 하지만
Alison, I can't, but
네가 그 시간들을 잊도록
내가 도울 수 있는
I promise I will do everything I can
모든 걸 하겠다고 약속하마
to help you forget them.
너 이거 기억나니?
Uhh... do you remember this?
너를 잃어버린 그 밤 이후로
지갑에 간직해 왔지
I've had it my wallet
since the night we lost you.
(breathing heavily)
This is the little girl
I refuse to let go off.
이게 내가 떠나보내길 거부했던
그 작은 소녀란다
(sobbing)
얘야, 그걸 알았으면 한다
Honey I need to know that
(clears throat) your mom and I...
네 엄마와 난...
우린 더 이상 함께 살지 않는단다
we aren't living together anymore.
Uh... we decided a few
months ago to get a divorce.
음...우린 몇 달 전에
이혼하기로 결정했어
알아요. 저 때문이라는 것두요
I'm sorry, Dad.
미안해요, 아빠
So am I.
나도 미안하다
(gunshot)
죽었어!
She's dead!
(violin playing)
(playing continues)
(phone beeping)
ARIA: Hanna what's going on?
한나 무슨 일이야?
도저히 모르겠다구...내 말은,
누가 그걸 보냈을까?
I have no idea... I mean,
who do you think sent it?
Sent what?
뭘 보내?
Hold on... Emily and Spencer
seriously didn't tell you?
잠깐...에밀리랑 스펜서가
정말 말해주지 않은 거?
Not tell me what?
뭘 말해주지 않아?
우린 네가 아직은
HANNA: We thought you were freaked out
about everything still.
안정되지 못했다고 생각했어
Uh... Ha... Hanna, talk to me.
으...한...한나, 말해 봐
알리가 문자메세지를 받았는데
Ali got a message on her phone,
she saw it when she opened
경찰서에서 가방을 열었을 때
그 메세지를 본 거고
up her purse at the police station,
that's why she lied to Holbrook.
그게 홀브룩 형사에게
거짓말을 한 이유였어
A message from "A?"
A에게서 온 메세지야?
"A" is dead already. Remember?
A는 이미 죽었잖아. 기억 안 나?
한나, 아직 안 자니?
WOMAN: Hanna, honey you still up?
I got to go.
가 봐야겠다
(phone drop tone)
(hinge creaking)
(doorbell rings)
Good morning. May I come in?
안녕하세요
들어가도 될까요?
물론이죠
Of course.
번거롭게 해드려서 죄송합니다
MR. DiLAURENTIS: I'm sorry to bother you.
제발요. 번거롭게 하신거 아니예요
Please. You are not bothering me.
I've been thinking about your family.
당신의 가족에 대해 생각해 봤어요
Ashley, I need your help.
애쉴리, 당신의 도움이 필요해요
알겠어요
Okay.
커피 좀 드릴까요?
Can I offer you some coffee?
이게 당신과 제시카를 위해
좋은 일인지 판단이 안 서네요
I can't imagine what this must
be like for you and Jessica.
제시카의 소식을 들었나요?
Have you heard from her?
아니요
No.
오늘 사무실에 가지 않았거든요
I didn't go to office today.
내 딸이 살아서 집에 있습니다
Our daughter is alive and home.
그리고 그 엄마가
딸을 만나지 않았어요
And her own mother
isn't there to greet her.
Where is she?
그녀는 어디있는 거죠?
난 믿어요. 제시카는
앨리슨이 집에 있는 걸 모르는 거라구요
I have to believe. Jessica
doesn't know that Alison's home.
You know the things have not
been good between me and her.
저와 제시카 사이가
좋지 않았다는 걸 당신은 알지요
그녀는 비밀번호를 바꿨고
저는 알 수가 없습니다
가능하다면 당신이
그녀의 이메일을 확인해 주세요
If you could go through her email.
오! 전...저는
어떻게 하는지 몰라요
Oh! I... I don't know if I could do that.
제이슨은 제시카가 어디 있는지
알 수도 있지 않나요?
Is there a chance Jason
might know where she is?
오! 제이슨은 말도 마세요
Oh! Forget about Jason.
충격을 받아서인지
Maybe he is in a state of shock
or maybe his brain is so deadened
약물이 뇌를 죽여버린 건지
그놈은 더 이상
인간같은 행동을 할 수 없어요
from drugs that he can't act
like a human being anymore.
He hasn't shed a tear
since he saw his sister.
제 여동생을 보고도
눈물 한 방울 흘리지 않더군요
충격을 받아서 일 거예요
I'm guessing that's shock.
Please...
부탁드립니다
도와주십시요
Help me.
(birds chirping)
뭐 하는 거야?
What are you doing?
Ali, you can't be out here.
알리, 넌 여기 있으면 안 돼
길가에 차량이
열 대 정도는 있다구, 알아?
There is about 10 cars at the
end of our street. Alright?
기자에, 경찰에
Press, police.
온 동네를 돌면서
춤을 추는 것도 아니잖아
I'm not twerking through town.
알겠어?
Okay?
그저 현관에 앉고 싶을 뿐이라구
I just wanna sit on my porch.
내게 어떤 질문도 하지 않고 있어
You haven't asked me any questions.
How come?
어째서지?
Figured you might need your space.
너의 공간이 필요했을 거라 이해했어
What was mom's reaction?
엄마의 반응은 어땠어?
When she found out I was still alive?
내가 살아 있다는 걸 아셨을 때?
할 말을 잃으셨었지
뭘 기대한 거니?
She was stunned. What do you expect?
들어가 있어
Get inside.
(door opens)
Can I help you?
무슨 일이죠?
딜로렌티스 부인과
약속이 있는데요
I've an appointment with Mrs. DiLaurentis.
누구시죠?
Who are you?
Kathy Paras. County shelter.
케이시 파라스예요
동물 보호소에서 나왔어요
We arranged to bring
Puppy over this morning.
오늘 아침에 강아지를 데려오기로
우린 약속을 했었어요
Mrs. DiLaurentis wants to adopt him.
딜로렌티스 부인이
이 녀석을 키우길 원했어요
- Sit.
- (dog barking)
앉아
착하구나
Good, boy.
My mother didn't order this.
어머니는 이걸 주문하지 않으셨어요
It's a dog, cowboy, not a pizza.
이건 개예요, 피자가 아니라구요
- 그리고 어머니가 요청하신 거예요
- 정말 영리하네요
- And she did.
- He is so smart.
Yeah.
그래요
어쩌다가 이녀석은
보호소로 간 거죠?
Why was he at the shelter?
Oh! He's got issues mostly with men.
오! 대부분의 개들과 같은 이유죠
그 개를 밴으로 도로 가져 가요
Put him back in the van.
Now!
당장요!
What happens to him if we don't take him?
우리가 데려가지 않으면
얘는 어떻게 되나요?
Basically, Mrs. D. was
the last stop on his train.
사실, D부인이
녀석의 여정에서 종착점이었죠
좋진 않지요
It's not pretty.
(music playing)
Do you need any help?
도와 줄까?
Oh, hey. Um.
오, 안녕, 음
No.
아니야
I got it. (music continues)
내가 할게
앨리슨에 대해 들었지?
Hey, you heard about Alison, right?
그 누나 살아 있어
She's alive.
그녀에게 일어난 일은
정말 우여곡절이었어
Pretty twisted what happened to her.
대단한 이야기지
Quite a story.
그 싸이코 녀석은
다음 희생자를 물색하기 위해
That psycho is probably circling this town
마을 주위를 배회할 거야
looking for his next victim.
그게 우리가 반격해야 할 이유지
Which is why we need to fight back.
박스에 있는 건 뭐야?
What's in the box?
Whistles.
호루라기
학교의 모든 여학생들에게
하나씩 주려고 주문했어
I ordered one for every girl in the school.
그리고 우리 모두의 핸드폰에
And I'm asking the principal to get us all
특별한 어플을 설치해달라고
교장선생님께 요청하고 있어
special apps for our phones.
It's either this or we all
hire full-time bodyguards.
그걸 해 주던지 아니면
풀타임 보디가드를 고용해 달라고
그래. 그 일을 신청해야겠는 걸
Yeah. I would apply for that job
if you could stand being
around me that much.
네가 많은 시간을
내 주변에 있을 수 있다면 말이야
가 봐야겠다
헤켓 교장선생님이 기다리셔
I gotta go. Principal
Hackett is waiting for me.
모나...
Mona...
니가 그리워
I miss you.
(door opens)
Em?
엠?
기다려. 우리 엄마가
집에 붙어 있으라고 하셨잖아
Wait up. My mom said us
to stay close to home.
학교에 가는 게 아냐
I am not going to school.
알리의 전화기를
돌려 주려는 것 뿐이야
I'm just giving Ali's phone back to her.
한나가 그 문자에 대해서
아리아에게 말했대
Hanna told the Aria about the text.
- 걔는 왜 그런거래?
- 왜냐하면 한나니까요
- Why would she do that?
- Because she's Hanna.
And now Aria is freaked out.
그래서 지금 아리아는 멘붕이야
She thinks A is back
and she's one text away
A가 돌아왔고
경찰에 진술해서
그 문자로부터 벗어나야 한다고
생각하고 있어
from being turned into the police.
- A는 죽었어
- 그래 그건 알아. 하지만...
- A is dead.
- Yeah, I know that. But...
but part of me thinks that
그 문자는
앨리슨이 돌아온 걸 환영하는
제나의 방식일 수도 있다고 생각해
that text was Jenna's way
of welcoming Alison home.
우린 제나나 다른 이들을 다룰 수 있어
우린 다섯이지만 제나는 혼자라구
We can handle Jenna and others,
five of us and one of her.
Yeah, but we killed that hers... her.
그래, 우린 죽였지
제나의...샤나를
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거야?
어제 밤에 제이슨이 뭘 던진건지
우린 보지 못 했잖아
We never looked last night
to see what Jason threw out,
and we probably should
have... look at this,
우린 봤어야 했을...이거 봐
제이슨이 언제 뉴욕에 있었지?
when was Jason in New York?
That's why no rush.
그게 혼란스러워하지 않는 이유였어
미안한데, 지금
네 필리핀 할머니 따라하는 거니?
Sorry, you channeling your
Filipino grandmother right now?
To see Alison.
앨리슨을 보러 가야겠어
We... we knew that his whole visit
우린...제이슨 오빠가
재활원에 있었다는 것이
to rehab was a big fat lie.
완전 뻥이었다는 걸 알고 있잖아
제이슨 오빠가
몇 주동안 앨리슨을 추적한 거라면?
What if he is been following her for weeks?
D부인이 제이슨을 시켜서
앨리슨을 몇 년이나 몇 달 동안 쫓았을 수도
What if Mrs. D's had him
tracking her for months, years.
제이슨 오빠가
그 문자를 보낸 거라 생각하는 거야?
Do you think Jason sent that text?
스펜서, 알리가
모든 사실을 말한 거라면
Spencer, if Ali told the whole truth,
알리의 엄마는
신고를 했어야 했을 거야
her mother would go down.
If Mrs. D thought that
someone just killed her child,
누군가가 자신의 자식을
죽였다고 생각한다면
자신의 다른 자식이 아니라면
왜 D부인이 보호하는 거겠어?
who else would she cover
for besides her other one?
(song playing)
(song fades)
(violin playing)
(another violin playing)
알리, 이건 우연의 일치가 아니야
Ali, it can't be a coincidence.
제이슨 오빠는 우리와 같은 밤에
뉴욕에서 돌아온 거야
Jason came back from New
York the same night as us.
오빠는 어제 밤에 내 방에 있었어
내가 자는 걸 보면서 말이야
He was in my room last
night, watching me sleep.
EMILY: Jason?
제이슨 오빠가?
세상에!
Oh my, God!
오늘 밤에 여기 있어선 안 돼
You can't stay here tonight,
you need to tell your dad
you wanna sleep at Spencer's.
스펜서네 집에서 자고 싶다고
아빠에게 말씀 드려
It's never gonna to happen.
어떤 일도 일어나지 않을 거야
빌어먹을 우체통까지 걸어가는 것도
허락되지 않는다구
I mean, he won't even let me
walk to the freaking mailbox.
Where are you in this, Spencer?
여기 있는 거니, 스펜서?
한 마디도 하지 않고 있잖아
You haven't even said a word.
내가 우리 오빠를 두려워 해야 돼?
Should I be afraid of our big brother?
I know you told him. Don't sweat it.
네가 오빠에게 말한 걸 알아
신경 쓰지 마
I'm even starting to think
that my dad knows too.
우리 아빠 역시도 아신다고 생각해
So you think Jason is the one
그래서 넌
내 머리에 돌을 날린 사람이
that slammed that rock in my head?
제이슨 오빠라고 생각하는 거야?
I mean, is that why my mom
has just magically disappeared
내가 집에 오기로 결정하자마자
우리 엄마가 마술같이 사라진 것이
as soon as I decide to come home?
그 이유라고 생각하는 거고?
I don't know. Maybe.
모르겠어. 그럴 수도 있겠지
And you were needling both of
our families with that secret,
그리고 넌 그 비밀 때문에
너의 가족과 우리 가족들의 신경을 긁고 있었고
they probably both wanted you to shut up.
두 가족은 아마도
네가 입을 다물길 원했을 거야
So you think that's why he went after me?
그래서 넌 그 이유가
오빠가 나를 쫓은 거라 생각해?
분명하게 말할 순 없지만
네 엄마가 너 대신 오빠를 택했다면
I can't say for sure, but if
your mom did choose him over you
아줌마는 남은 우리들을
나쁘게 보이게 할 모든 이유가 있었고
she had every reason to
make the rest of us look bad,
and we've been framed as pathological liars
그 이후로 우린
병적인 거짓말쟁이들로
ever since then.
뒤집어 쓰게 된 거야
So if we ever did find out who hit you,
네 머리를 친 사람을
찾아내지 못 한다면
nobody would even believe us.
누구도 우리를 믿지 않을 거야
Wow. You really have given it some thought.
와우. 넌 정말
여러가지 생각거리를 주는 구나
Look, my mom comes back tomorrow.
야, 우리 엄마는 내일 오셔
You can stay with us.
우리와 함께 있어도 돼
Emily, I just got back,
에밀리, 난 막 돌아왔고
my dad's not going to
let me out for sleepovers.
우리 아빠는 친구 집에서 자는 걸
허락하지 않으실 거야
그럼, 대체 뭘 하려는데?
Well, what're you going to do?
내게 몇 가지 생각이 있어
I have a few ideas.
Well, can you let us in on them?
그럼, 우리에게
그 생각들을 알려줄래?
그래야 우리가 따라잡기 위해서
So that we're not caught
paddling around like idiots
멍청이들 같이
허우적 거리지 않겠지?
trying to play catch-up?
내가 말했잖아 스펜서...
I told you Spencer...
아리아를 보호하기 위해
거짓말을 지어냈다고
I made up that lie to protect Aria.
아리아는 누군가를 죽인 거라구, 기억해?
She kind of killed someone, remember?
우리와 먼저 상의했어야지
You could have consulted us first.
알았어, 얘들아, 제발 그만해
Okay, guys, please stop.
이미 엎질러진 물이야
What's done is done.
지금은 우리를 무너뜨리려는 사람에게
우리의 힘을 모아야 돼
We need to focus our energy
on who's trying to sink us now.
이제 일어났니?
Hey, you just got up?
네, 뭐하시는 거예요?
Yeah, what you're doing?
난, 음...
I'm, um...
앨리슨의 아빠를 위해
뭔가를 하고 있지
doing some work for Alison's father.
제시카가 있을만한 곳을
내가 알아내길 원하셨거든
He wants me to get a lead
on where Jessica might be.
제시카의 이메일 몇 개를
열어보려 해 봤는데
I'm... I was about to
open up some of her emails,
난...할 수가 없구나
and I... I just can't do this.
Why?
왜요?
Hanna, the last thing I
wanna do is get in the middle
한나, 난 이혼 과정에 있는
of two people who are
going through divorce,
두 사람 사이에서
중립적이고 싶어
and it's not just an invasion of privacy...
이건 단지
프라이버시의 침해는 아니지만...
it feels like a betrayal.
배신하는 것 같은 기분이야
Well, I'm betting Mrs. D
would rather have you looking
D부인에겐 경찰 보다는
엄마가 이메일을 조사하는 것이
더 나을것이라는데 걸겠어요
through her emails than the police.
And besides, Ali needs her mom right now.
게다가, 알리는 지금
엄마가 필요하다구요
(phone ringing)
(ringing continues)
WOMAN: Take milk or sugar?
- 우유를 넣을까? 아님 설탕?
- 우유가 좋죠
MAN: Milk is great.
안녕
Hi.
- When did you get back?
- Mm... late last night.
- 언제 돌아온 거야?
- 어제 밤 늦게
This morning... I don't
know I think I had dinner
오늘 아침인가...두 대륙에서
저녁 식사를 했다고
생각한건지 모르겠다
on two continents.
Why didn't you call me?
왜 전화하지 않았어?
그래, 난...잠시 들러야겠다고 생각했고
널 보게 된 거야
No, I... I thought I'd come by and see you.
Why? What's going on?
왜? 무슨 일인데?
Melissa told your father and me that she
멜리사는 네 아빠와 내게
런던에서 토비를 봤고
그래서 급히 돌아온 거라고 말했었어
saw Toby in London,
that's why she rushed back,
하지만 그런 일은 없었어
but apparently that never happened.
What?
뭐라구요?
내가 멜리사를 보러 갔었는데
렌이 대문에서 대답하더라구
I went to her place,
Wren answered the door,
he said he was staying there,
렌이 거기서 지내고 있었고
and she wasn't in London anymore.
멜리사는 더 이상
런던에 없다는 거야
It doesn't make sense.
이해가 안 되는구나
Oh, if you want, you can call him.
오, 원하신다면
그와 통화해 보세요
Wren? Oh, please!
렌 말이냐? 오, 제발!
I'd rather stick a knife in the toaster.
*토스터기에 칼을 꽂고 말지
*토스터기에 칼을 꽂으면 폭발함
I have a client to meet in town,
난 마을에서
고객과 약속이 있지만
넌 집에 붙어 있거라
you on the other hand
are staying close to home.
- Is that clear?
- Yes.
- 알겠니?
- 네
- 그래, 갈게
- 다녀 오세요
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
Bye.
간다
(door closes)
런던엔 왜 간거야?
Why did you go to London?
널 위한 대답을 원했었어
I wanted answers for you.
네 언니가 내 눈을 보며 말한다면
I figured if I could get your
sister to look me in the eye
- and tell me something.
- Something truthful?
- 뭔가를 말해줄 거라 생각했지
- 뭔가 진실한 걸?
맞아
- Do you know about...
- Alison?
- 알고 있니? 그거에 관해...
- 앨리슨에 대해서?
Yeah.
그래
꽤 이상한 얘기를 들었지만
I've heard some pretty weird stuff
but I'd rather hear it from you.
네게 듣고 싶어
아리아
Aria.
Sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
미안. 놀래키려던 건 아니었어
네 문자를 막 확인했어
알리와 있었거든
Just got your text... I was with Ali.
뭐 하는 거니?
What are you doing?
한 달동안 여기에
앨리슨을 숨겨 두었다면
If we've been out here
hiding her for a month
it sure as hell needs
start looking like it.
확실히 그렇게 보이게 할 필요가 있어
지금 이럴 필요는 없어
Seriously, you can't do this right now.
그래, 네가 맞아
Yeah, you're right.
앨리슨이 문자를 받은 후에
We should have been out
here last night filling this
우린 어제 밤, 이 빌어먹을 것들로
여기를 채웠어야 했다구
place with crap after Alison got that text.
오, 그리고 그걸 내게
비밀로 해 줘서 고맙구나
Oh, and thank you for keeping
me in the dark about that.
난 뭐니? 니들의 애야?
What am I? Your child?
네 아빠가 경찰서에 오시면
네가 충격을 받을 거니까
We only did that because you
were such a mess when your dad
우리가 그랬던 거야
/ 그래서 어쩔 건데?
- came to the police station.
- Yeah and what?
내가 속 편하게 잘 자고
What you thought if I
got a good night's sleep,
아침에 즐겁게 일어날 거라
생각했던 거니?
I'd just wake up in candy land?
알았어, 아리아 진정해
Okay, Aria calm down.
- 그 문자는 A로부터 온 게 아니야
- 네가 그걸 어떻게 알아?
- That text wasn't from "A".
- How do you know that?
샤나, 그 A가 죽을 때
난 거기 있었으니까
Because I was there when
Shana-slash-A was killed.
봐봐...스펜서가 옳았어
Look... Spencer was right.
알리의 이야기는
한 가지 일만 부인하는 것이 아니라
It's one thing not to
contradict Ali's story
또 다른 거짓말을 더하게 한다구
and it's another to add to it.
우린 다시
토끼굴로 내려갈 순 없어
We can't go down that rabbit hole again.
그래, 난 그러지 않을 거야, 알겠어?
Yeah, well, I can't do nothing, all right?
내가 샤나를 죽인 걸
A가 알고 있을 거니까
Because if "A" knows
that I took down Shana,
- 아리아...
- 내가 해야 하는 ...
- Aria...
- I'm going to be the...
샤나는 몇 달동안 우리를
연습용 타겟으로 이용했었고
Shana had been using us as
target practice for months,
네가 한 건 순전히
what you did was purely
자기 방어야
/ 그게 문제가 아니야
- self-defense.
- I doesn't matter.
누군가가 죽었어
Someone is dead.
그래, 샤나는 다시 살아날 수도
그녀에게 사과할 수도
All right, and she will never
be able to recover or apologize
심지어 고등학교를 졸업할 수도 없어
내가 그녀를 죽였으니까
or even graduate from high
school because I killed her.
내가 그녀를 죽였다고, 에밀리
그리고 그 사실을 가지고
I killed her, Emily, and I
don't know how I'm gonna be able
어떻게 살아가야 할지 모르겠다구
to live with that.
(breathes heavily)
아리아...
Aria...
그 상황에선
네가 죽던지, 샤나가 죽던지였어
in that moment, it was you or her.
난 겪은 적이 있어...
I went through this after...
네이트 말이야
Nate.
You think that no one can
understand what this feels like,
넌 누구도 이 기분을
이해할 수 없을 거라 생각하지만
난 거기에 있었어
but I've been there.
(empty can clinking)
Remember, we used to sneak out here?
여기에 몰래
숨어들어오곤 하던거 기억나?
우리의 가장 큰 문제는
Our biggest problem was
치아교정기를 한 상태로
어떻게 땅콩버터를 먹느냐 하는 거였는데
how to eat peanut butter with braces.
(car honking)
프린터에 용지는 충분히 있니?
Is there enough paper in that printer?
네, 거기에 몇 장 있을 거예요
Uh, yeah there should be
a couple of pages in there,
몇 장 가져다 드릴까요?
do you want me to get you some more?
아니다, 알겠어. 내가 할게
No, that's all right. I'll get it.
_
수신 : 이름 없음
제목 : 제목 없음
_
-
발신 : 제시카 딜로렌티스
수신 : 이름 없음
더 이상 널 보호할 수 없어
_
♪ I'll be your light, your
match your burning sun ♪
♪ I'll be the bright, in
black that's making you run ♪
♪ And we'll feel alright,
and we'll feel alright ♪
♪ Cause we'll work it out,
yes we'll work it out ♪
♪ I'll be doin' this,
if you had a doubt ♪
♪ Till the love runs out,
'til the love runs out ♪
♪ I'll be your ghost,
your game, your stadium ♪
The next time you go to London...
다음에 런던에 가게 되면...
Yeah.
응
You're taking me with you.
나도 데리고 가
그리고 우린
절대 돌아오지 않는 거지
And we're never coming back.
♪ I'll be doin' this,
if you ever doubt ♪
네가 떠난다면
언론에서 뭐라고 하겠니?
MR. DiLAURENTIS: What's so
pressing that you have to leave?
What's in Philly? Or should I ask, who?
필라델피아엔 왜?
누구에게 가는지 물어도 되니?
I need to drop something off to a friend.
친구에게 뭐 좀 갖다줘야 해요
- 당장 말이냐?
- 저녁식사 후라고 말씀드렸잖아요
- Right now?
- I said after dinner.
Your sister has been gone for nearly a...
네 여동생은 거의 몇 년 동안...
그럼 걔가 잠들 때까지
제가 기다려야 하겠군요?
Then I will wait till
she goes asleep, okay?
어떻게 그 아이를
잠들 수 있게 할 거라 생각하니?
What makes you think she can sleep?
그 아이의 엄마는
아직도 여기 없고
Her mother is still not
here, and I am thinking
그녀가 어디 있는지 알고 있는
유일한 사람이 너라고 생각하고 있다
you're the only one who knows where she is.
마음대로 생각하세요
저는 모르니까요
Think what you want. I don't.
Jason, every time someone in this family
제이슨, 우리 가족 중 누구라도
이 집에서 걸어 나갈 때마다
walks out of this house it's a news story
뉴스거리가 되고 있고
and the last thing I want is you speaking
내가 정말로 원하는 건
네가 그 빌어먹을 리포터에게
말하는 것이다
to a damn reporter.
Ow, don't worry, Dad...
오, 걱정 마세요, 아버지...
I won't embarrass you
anymore than I already have.
더 이상은 예전처럼
아버지를 곤란하게 만들지 않을테니까요
Emily... I didn't know you were here.
에밀리...여기 있는지 몰랐었구나
알리가 페페를
산책시켜달라고 부탁해서요
Ali asked me to take Pepe for a walk.
Whose dog is that?
저건 누구 개냐?
너 집에 개를 가져온 거냐?
You brought home a dog?
오늘 아침에 왔어요
It was dropped off this morning.
- 엄마가 보호소에서 그 개를 구했데요
- 그래?
- Mom rescued him from the shelter.
- Really?
Well, maybe when you go
to Philly you can tell her
그럼 필라델피아에 가면
네 엄마에게 말해줄 수도 있겠구나
there is more than a dog
waiting for her back home.
집으로 돌아오길 기다리는 개 보다
더 큰 이유가 있다고 말이다
I can't do anymore.
더는 못 먹겠어
죽기살기로 해 보려는 거 아니였어?
Are you gonna to go for it?
- No, go ahead.
- You wanted it.
- 아냐, 됐어
- 니가 원한 거 였잖아
(door slams)
- 안녕, 아리아
- 어디 갔었어?
- Hello, Aria.
- Hey, where have you been?
Dad told me to order dinner.
아빠가 저녁 주문하래서
- 여기에 야채...
- 배 안 고파
- There is a veggie...
- I'm not hungry.
Were you walking around in
the dark all by yourself?
어두운데 혼자서 돌아다닌 거야?
- 뭐라구?
- 앨리슨에게 일어난 일도 있는데
- Excuse me?
- Given what happened to Alison
경찰의 에스코트도 없이
I can't believe you would walk to the curb
함부로 돌아다니다니
믿을 수가 없다
without a police escort.
내가 이거 빌렸었어...다시
Hey, I borrowed this... again.
네가 빌렸었다니 무슨 말이야?
What do you mean you borrowed it?
내가 갖진 않지만
간수하는 것과 같은 거지
As in, I didn't take it and keep it.
Why would you borrow it at all?
대체 이걸 왜 빌린 거야?
사회학 스터디 때문에
'Cause I needed to put some music together
음악 몇 개를
모아둘 필요가 있었거든
for a social studies project.
그거였나...
It was that...
that violin music. Was
that coming from your room
그 바이올린 음악 말이야
네 방에서 나오던
- last night?
- I guess...
- 어제 밤에?
- 그럴 걸...
미안. 내 자켓 갖고 와서
집에 데려다 줄게
Sorry. I will grab my
jacket and take you home.
도서관에 데려다 주면 돼
You can drop me at the library.
아직 조사할 것이 좀 있거든
I still have some research to do.
- Mona?
- Yeah?
- 모나?
- 응?
너는 조사를 도서관이나
이 집에서 하는 거니?
You doing your research in
the library or in this house?
Your brother invited me to dinner.
네 동생이 저녁 식사에 초대한 거야
But I am actually really glad to see you
하지만 너를 보게 되서
정말로 기뻐
because I can give you this in person.
직접 네게
이걸 줄 수 있어서 말이야
Go on take it.
가져 가
I've got hundreds more.
난 백 개도 넘게 있어
If anything else, we can
use what happened to Alison
앨리슨과 같은 일을 당하면
사용할 수 있어
경고 정도로는
누구도 안전할 수 없어
as a wakeup call, nobody is safe.
What are you trying to prove, Mona?
무얼 증명하려는 거지, 모나?
- Is this a threat?
- No, it's a whistle.
- 협박하는 거야?
- 아니, 이건 호루라기야
입술에 대고 불기만 하면 돼
You put it between your lips and blow.
We all know where you were the
night that Alison disappeared.
앨리슨이 사라지던 밤에 네가 어디 있었는지
우리 모두는 알고 있어
She told us about the
time you spent together
로스트 우드에 있는 모텔 방에서
너와 시간을 보냈었다고
at the Lost Woods motel room.
앨리슨이 우리에게 말해줬어
너 스스로 입닥쳐야 할
이야기가 몇가지 있지 않아?
You have a few stories of your
own to keep quiet, don't you?
Tell me... how is Mr. Fitz doing?
말해 줘...
핏츠 선생님은 어떻게 지내?
Will he make a full recovery?
완전히 회복될 수 있으려나?
MIKE: Can I have the car keys?
자동차 키 좀 줄 수 있어?
누나
Aria.
D부인이 명상센터에
가신 적이 있었어요
There is a meditation center
that Mrs. D once went to,
거기에 전화해 보시는 것도...
you can try calling there...
Thank you, Hanna, and
thank your mother for me.
고맙다, 한나
그리고 어머니께도 감사드린다
우린 막 저녁식사를 하고 있었어
We were just about to have dinner.
If you girls want to join us?
너희들도 함께 하지 않으련?
- 그럼요
- 우린...오늘은 안 돼요
- Sure.
- We... we can't tonight.
Uhh... right. Maybe tomorrow.
아...맞아요
내일은 가능할 거예요
Anytime.
언제든 좋다
What's going on? Why can't I eat dinner?
무슨 일이야?
왜 저녁 먹을 수 없는데?
Just get in the car. I've
to show you something.
차에 타기나 해
보여줄 게 있으니까
It's an update on Mrs. D.
D부인에 대한 정보야
Ali's dad thinks he's hiding her in Philly.
알리의 아빠는
부인이 필라델피아에 숨어 있다고 생각하셔
잠깐, 누가 부인을 숨겨?
Wait, who's hiding her?
Jason.
제이슨 오빠가
Jason told his dad he had
to drop something off to
제이슨 오빠가
필라델피아에 있는 친구에게
a friend in Philly.
무얼 갖다 주러 간다고 하더라구
Could that be code for New York?
뉴욕에 관한 정보야?
What is this?
이게 뭐야?
D부인이 마을을 빠져나간 밤에
그 메일을 작성했지만
Mrs. D wrote that email the
night that she escaped town,
메일을 보내지는 않았어
but she never sent it.
It says, "I can't protect you anymore".
더 이상 널 보호할 수 없어 라고 썼다구
누구에게 쓴 메일이겠어?
Who would she have written that to?
(both gasp)
(breathing heavily)
무슨 일이죠, 제이슨 오빠?
What's up, Jason?
I just saw what you delivered.
네가 전해주는 걸 봤어
Your dad asked my mother...
오빠의 아빠가
우리 엄마에게 부탁해서...
그래, 우리 엄마가 한 게 아니지
Yeah, well, my mother didn't.
그러니까, 해당사항 없는 사람들은
So, maybe it is time people
stay the hell out of places
꺼져버려야 할 때 일 거야
they don't belong.
너희들을 포함해서 말이야
That includes you.
Follow him.
쫓아가
No, you follow him. I have
to change my underwear.
안 돼, 네가 쫓아가
나 속옷 갈아 입어야 해
한나, 서둘러. 알겠어?
Hanna, hurry up. Okay?
엄마를 보러 가는 걸 거야
He might be going to see his mother.
서두르라고!
Hurry up!
제이슨의 엄마가
저기 있을리는 없어
There is no way his mom's in there.
Mrs. D wouldn't even walk down this street.
D부인은 이 거리로 오진 않았을 거야
Why not?
안 될 게 뭐야?
부인이 숨어 있는 거라면
빈민가에 숨을 거라고
If she's hiding out she's
not going to be doing it
at the Four Seasons.
생각하진 않을테니까
제이슨이 누른 벨을 찾아야 돼
We need to ring the buzzer he pressed.
D부인이 응답할지도. 해보자...
Maybe Mrs. D will answer. Come on...
이거 였나?
이게 아니면 저거였나?
Was it this one? Or
was it, was it that one?
Who are you looking for?
누굴 찾는 거요?
뭘 도와드릴까?
Well, can I help you?
Umm...
음...
I... I... I heard that
there might be a vacancy
저는...저는...저는
빈방이 있을 거라고 들어서요
available for a sub-let.
임대놓을 수 있는
임대라고?
Sub-let?
Who... who... who told you that, huh?
누가...누가...
누가 그런 말을 했어, 어?
But, who are you?
너희들 누구야?
정말 부동산 업자야? 꺼져버려
A real estate agent? Get out of here.
Now!
당장!
둘다 꺼져버려!
Both of youse. Go!
- (phone beeping)
- (music playing)
You don't want to get that?
전화 안 받을 거야?
No.
응
- (music continues)
- (beeping continues)
(phone beeping again)
누군가 정말 너와 통화하고 싶나부다
Someone really wants to reach you.
걔네들 기다릴 수 있어
Well, they can wait.
Spence, what's going on?
스펜스, 무슨 일이야?
Nothing.
아무 것도
앨리슨에 관한 거야?
Does it have to do with Alison?
(sighs)
아니야
No.
Is this about Melissa?
멜리사에 관한 건가?
No.
아니야
(sound of footsteps)
Did you follow me?
날 따라온 거야?
I'm not supposed to be out of my house,
집에서 나올 생각은 아니었지만
but I had to come here to say goodbye.
작별인사를 위해
여기 와야만 했어
저기에 놓여 있는 저 소녀는,
그녀는 정말 죽었잖아
The girl they made that
for, she really is gone.
I can't be that person anymore, Mona.
난 더 이상
저 소녀일 순 없었어, 모나
I know you hated me
날 증오한다는 걸 알고
and wanted me to go straight to hell.
내가 지옥으로 떨어지길
원한다는 걸 알아
지옥에 가는 건 쉽지만...
Going there is easy...
it's the coming back that's hard...
거기에서 돌아오는 건 어려워....
But you and me... we,
we understand each other.
하지만 너와 난...
우린, 우린 서로를 이해하잖아
I need you, Mona.
네가 필요해, 모나
As a friend.
친구로서 말이야
The truth will bury you
in a New York minute.
뉴욕에서 있었던 사실이
널 묻어버릴 거다
네가 궁금해하던 건
In case you're wondering,
that was me, I sent that text.
그건 나였어, 내가 보낸 문자야
I guess I should have
signed my name because
내 이름을 써서 보낼 걸 그랬어
I don't have to pretend
to be anyone else anymore.
난 더 이상 다른
누군가인 척 할 수 없을테니까
I don't have to hide. You do.
난 숨을 수 없어
네가 그러듯이 말이야
And you're gonna wish you stayed dead.
그리고 넌 죽은 상태였던 게
더 좋았을 거야
오늘 밤에 경찰서에 가야겠어
그래야만 해
I'm going to the cops tonight, I have to.
얘들아...난...
난 이 짓 못 하겠어
You guys... I... I can't hold on to this.
- Aria breathe.
- Can you please wait
- 아리아 숨 좀 쉬어
- 좀 기다려 줄래?
여기에 우리 모두 모여서
의논해 보자
and discuss this with all of us here?
Where is Spencer?
스펜서는 어딨어?
우리가 여기서 알리를
몰래 만날 수 있도록
She went next door to distract
Mr. DiLaurentis so we could
딜로렌티스 씨의 주의를 분산시키기 위해
옆 집에 갔어
sneak Ali over here.
제이슨이 오늘 밤에
그리 오래 머물진 않을테니까
She better haul us because I'm
guessing Jason is not making
too many more stops tonight.
스펜서가 잘 끌어줄 거야
Guys, please, enough
with Jason for a minute.
얘들아, 제발, 제이슨은 됐다구
Mona knows that we were in
New York. Don't you understand?
모나는 우리가 뉴욕에 있었던 걸
알고 있다구. 알겠니?
Okay, it's only a matter of time
before she runs out of whistles
모나가 호루라기를 다 처리하고
우리의 계획을 산산조각을 내고
and start tearing our balloons
and say Aria killed Shana.
아리아가 샤나를 죽였다 라고 말하는 건
시간 문제일 뿐이라구
- 호루라기라구?
- 아리아, 그만. 괜찮아
- Okay, whistles?
- Aria, stop. Okay.
Mona does not know about Shana.
모나는 샤나의 일을 알지 못 해
그렇다면 누구야? 누구?
누가 날 엿 먹이는 거지?
Then who does? Who?
Who is screwing with me?
And you keep me telling
me that "A" is dead.
그리고 너희들은
나에게 A는 죽었다고 했잖아
"A" is dead, Aria.
A는 죽었어, 아리아
Then why am I hearing
a violin in my backyard?
그렇다면 왜 뒷 마당에서
바이올린 소리가 들리는 거지?
빌어먹을 지붕위의 바이올린
연주자는 누구냐구?
Who's the fiddler on my freaking roof?
아리아, 우리 말 좀 들어
제이슨은 뉴욕에 있었어
Hey, Aria, listen to us.
Jason was the one in New York.
그가 알리를 위협해서
납치를 당했다는 거짓말을 하게 한 걸
Once we can prove that he
is a threat that made Ali
tell that kidnapping lie then...
증명하기만 하면...
But how're we doing that?
하지만 어떻게 그렇게 하지?
나도 모르지
그게 우리가 모여야 할 이유야
I don't know, that's why
we're having a meeting.
Once the police are on to Mrs. D and Jason,
일단 경찰이 D부인과
제이슨을 연행하면
then everything we've done can be explained
그 때엔 우리가 했던
모든 것을 설명하고
앨리슨은 마침내
진실을 말할 수 있는 거야
and Alison can finally tell the truth.
(sound of footsteps)
(door rumbles)
알리
Ali.
거기 누구 없어요?
Hey you up there?
Hello?
여기요?
늦은 시간이구나
JASON: It's late.
걔는 잠들었을 거야
She may be asleep.
아님, 쓰레기를
가져 가려고 들린 거니?
Or did you come by to take out the trash?
Jason...
제이슨 오빠...
알리가 로즈우드로 돌아온 밤에
뉴욕에 있었나요?
Were you in New York the night
that Ali came back to Rosewood?
Why? Why is that important?
왜? 그게 왜 중요한데?
I think you know why.
그 이유를 알 거라 생각하는데요
If you're trying to make a
squirm and run for cover because
오빠가 했던 일 때문에
빠져나가기 위해서
발버둥치는 거라면...
of something that you did...
내가 무슨 일을 했다고 생각하는데?
What is it you think I did?
You think I'm the one who kidnapped her?
내가 앨리슨을
납치했다고 생각하는 거냐?
Where did that theory come from, huh?
그 주장은 어디서 나온 거냐, 어?
My father?
우리 아버지가 그러시디?
- No.
- Really?
- 아니요
- 정말이냐?
아마도 아버지는 지금
통행을 제한하는 문제 때문에
'Cause he's probably down
at that precinct right now
sharing that theory with the cops.
경찰들과 의견을 조율하고 있어
우리 엄마가 아니라면
누가 아버지를 막겠어?
Without my mother, who's going to stop him?
Jason, why were you in New York?
오빠, 뉴욕엔 왜 있었나요?
(dog barking)
(dog groaning) Pepe.
페페
페페, 왜 그러니?
Pepe, what's wrong?
- (barking loudly)
- How did she know it's name?
개 이름을 어떻게 알지?
Whose dog is that?
저게 누구 개야?
Alison's.
앨리슨의 개야
알리는 언제 개를 구할 시간이 있었냐?
When did she had the time to get a dog?
(screaming)
세상에!
Oh, my God!
Grrrrr...
(barking loudly)
제이슨 오빠
(indistinct scream) Jason.
그러지 마요...안 돼요...
제이슨 오빠
Don't... no... Jason.
(barking loudly)
(breathing heavily)
♪ But if I never get to heaven ♪
♪ Will you fly away to me ♪
♪ And if I never get to heaven ♪
♪ Say you'll come and rescue me ♪
♪ Rescue me ♪
♪ Please catch my tears ♪
(indistinct conversation on police radio)
♪ Yeah... will you carry me ♪
♪ Or do I deserve to walk alone ♪
♪ Only farther than I've ever known ♪
♪ Don't leave me here on my own ♪
♪ And if I never get to heaven ♪
♪ Do you think I'll still be free ♪
♪ Say you'll come and be with me ♪
♪ Be with me ♪
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -